November 26, 2008… Terror struck the heart of India.
Hotel Mumbai is a thriller, history, drama film directed by Anthony Maras.
Mumbai, India, November 26, 2008.
While several terrorists spread hatred and death through the
city, others attack the Taj Mahal Palace Hotel.
Both hotel staff and guests risk their lives, making unthinkable sacrifices to
protect themselves and keep everyone safe while help arrives.
Arjun, played by Dev Patel.
David, played by Armie Hammer.
Zahra, played by Nazanin Boniadi.
Sally, played by Tilda Cobham-Hervey.
Chef Hemant Oberoi, played by Anupam Kher.
Vasili Orchevsky, played by Jason Isaacs.
Hotel Mumbai is a 2018 independent action thriller film directed by
Anthony Maras and co-written by Maras and John Collee.
An Indian-Australian-American co-production, it is inspired by the 2009 documentary Surviving
Mumbai about the 2008 Mumbai attacks at the Taj Mahal Palace Hotel in India.
The film stars Dev Patel, Armie Hammer, Nazanin Boniadi, Anupam Kher, Tilda
Cobham-Hervey, Jason Isaacs, Suhail Nayyar, Nagesh Bhosle, and Natasha Liu Bordizzo.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on 7 September 2018, and had
its Australian premiere at the Adelaide Film Festival on 10 October 2018.
The film was released in Australia and the United States on 14 and 22
March 2019, respectively, and in India on 29 November 2019.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, mumbai (bombay),
india, based on true story, india, struggle for survival.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and intense.